# **Jeffrey Thorslund**

Full Stack Web Developer

Software Engineer with 3 years of full stack web development experience and strong fundamentals in Front End technologies. Loves building projects that make big differences in small communities. Expert in React and test-driven development. Striving to become a masterful software craftsman.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Web Developer

November 2020 - May 2022

Semios | Vancouver, BC

- **Led implementation of farm mapping feature** to allow farm managers to plan and control pest trap placements on their orchards; resulted in over 1200 trap placements and feature adoption by 80% of major clients.
- Mentored a co-op student, teaching him about writing production quality code, managing software tasks, and testing practices.

# **Owner and Mobile Developer**

July 2020 - July 2022

Outer Flux Development | Vancouver, BC

- Lead a team of 2 developers to design, develop, and deploy an event sharing social media app. Tested by 20 early adopters.
- Followed Agile methodology to maintain continuous integration, automated testing, constant technical readiness to confidently deliver a streamlined product.

### **Full Stack Web Developer**

February 2020 – November 2020

Eulogato | Ottawa, ON

- Full Stack development of an assisted eulogy writing tool resulting in 180 eulogies created within two weeks of launch.
- Collaborating with creative writers to increase automated content variety causing users to complete the full workflow at 2.5x the previous rate.

#### **PROJECTS**

Rapid Riot - Whitewater Festival Database | Try it out | See the code Explore the largest collection of Whitewater Paddling Festivals in North America using an interactive map/list interface. Created and maintained by community contributions.

- Received 150 festival submissions from paddlers, organizers and sponsors within 5 days of launch.
- Fostered the paddling community by providing smaller festivals a platform to become discoverable to the greater kayaking community.

Mamquam Meltdown - Slalom Data Analytics | Try it out | See the code Module to instantly create analytics out of raw Slalom Paddling result data, presented on a Front End that was used in a real kayak slalom race.

- Used in a real slalom race in Squamish, B.C. to compile over 120 race times, for 60 racers at the event.
- 150% faster and 50% less error prone than manual calculation.
- Allowed the event organizers to perform the awards ceremony directly after the race, as no manual result compilation was required.

#### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Squamish, BC, Canada



613-316-9222



ieffreythorslund.com



jeffreythorslund@gmail.com



in /jeffrey-thorslund



(7) /ieffthorslund

#### **SKILLS**

### Languages:

- Javascript, Typescript
- HTML5, CSS3

#### Front End:

- · React, React Native
- Redux
- · SASS, LESS
- · Ant Design, Material UI

#### Back End:

- Node.js, Express
- · RESTful API, GraphQL
- · JWT Authentication, Auth0

#### Database:

- MongoDB, Mongoose ODM
- PostgreSQL
- · Firebase, Supabase

# Tools, Testing, Deployment:

- Jest, React Testing Library
- Heroku, Netlify, Expo
- · AWS, GCP
- Postman
- Git
- · Figma, Adobe Suite

# **EDUCATION**

Carleton University Bachelor of Enviro. Science Ottawa, ON — May 2019

#### **LEADERSHIP**

# **Outdoors Club of Carleton** University

President

Organized, led, and supervised a variety of outdoor trips for university students including canoeing, kayaking, whitewater rafting, hiking and rock climbing.